<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>chat.avia.AviaClient</id>
  <name>Avia Client</name>
  <icon type="remote">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AvaLilac/for-desktop/refs/heads/main/avia_assets/icon.ico</icon>
  <summary>Avia is an open-source modification of Stoat, an open-source, user-first chat platform</summary>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://stt.gg/2vNF0JzH</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://avalilac.github.io/AviaClient-Home/</url>
  <url type="contact">https://stt.gg/2vNF0JzH</url>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0</project_license>
  <requires>
    <internet>always</internet>
  </requires>
  <developer>
    <name>AvaLilac</name>
  </developer>
  <description>
  <p>The Stoat client you actually want</p>
  <p>Avia Client is a modification of Stoat, it allows for use of plugins and CSS themes with a bunch of pre-included features such as a menu for all your favorite gifs ! This Flatpak version is maintained by Raptor.</p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">chat.avia.AviaClient.desktop</launchable>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.6.0" date="2026-05-07">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/AvaLilac/for-desktop/compare/1.5.0...1.6.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changelog</p>
        <p>New</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Meet Aurora, our new mascot and logo (Created by Amelia in Procreate)</li>
          <li>There is now an integrated Repository for plugins and themes, allowing you to browse &amp; install them from within the client.</li>
          <li>With the new Headliner feature, you can change the titlebar of AviaClient to anything you like</li>
          <li>You can now fully backup and restore AviaClient's data (Themes, plugins, QuickCSS, etc)</li>
          <li>You can now Login with a session token</li>
          <li>Added a new About window, which can be access via the tray or by pressing F1</li>
          <li>Monaco is now used as the default editor for Plugins, Local Plugins, Themes, and QuickCSS</li>
          <li>Flatpak version</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Many, many Quality-of-Life changes under the hood for developers</li>
          <li>Rebranded the desktop app</li>
          <li>Local plugins can now be imported directly from a .js file</li>
          <li>Themes can now be imported directly from a .txt or .css file (via Drag-n-Drop too!)</li>
          <li>The Settings UI now properly displays that this is AviaClient</li>
          <li>You can now display the custom titlebar with the system's native menu buttons (close, minimize, maximize)</li>
          <li>The tray icon menu now has "Restart App"</li>
          <li>There's now an option to disable the show/hide behaviour of the tray icon upon clicking it</li>
          <li>Plugin installation is no longer limited to GitHub URLs - we now support Codeberg as well</li>
          <li>DevTools can now be opened by pressing F12</li>
          <li>Exposed a method to get AviaClient version via js (window.native.versions.aviaClient())</li>
          <li>AviaClient version is now displayed in the tray, alongside Stoat's</li>
          <li>Discord RPC now displays AviaClient</li>
          <li>macOS only: the default about window now uses AviaClient's version as the buildId</li>
          <li>macOS only: Settings can now be opened and closed by pressing Cmd + ,</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix the chatbar buttons being placed incorrectly under specific circumstances (by 0simp#2291)</li>
          <li>Fix a rare race condition during app initialization</li>
          <li>Fixed app badges being unable to be displayed - still needs badge logic</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.0" date="20/06/2026">
      <p>Changelog</p>
      <p>New</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Update checker: Lets you know when there is a new release of Avia Client.</li>
        <li>Custom badges: Expanded list of available badges.</li>
        <li>Flatpak support: Thanks to Raptor.</li>
        <li>What's new: A recreation of Stoat's What's New to display what's new in Avia Client.</li>
        <li>Avia Menu: A new menu has been added within the chat header.</li>
        <li>New API: Plugin Devs can register their own buttons using the API, which will appear inside the new menu.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Changes</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Avia Client Now uses its own storage. Meaning its a completely fresh install of Avia Client.</li>
        <li>Both Online and Local Plugins have both been given a UI revamp.</li>
        <li>Both Online and Local Plugins have had their plugin order reversed - the most recent plugins added now shows on top instead of bottom.</li>
        <li>Added @import url("") support to Themes (not QuickCSS). This allows you to load themes via a URL, allowing themes that either both local and parts of it online - or purely online.</li>
        <li>Font Loader has had a complete UI revamp, including support for Local fonts.</li>
        <li>The Trusted Repo now has the ability to Install Plugins to Local Plugins.</li>
        <li>Monaco has been updated to v0.50.</li>
        <li>MacOS: Aurora icon now supports Liquid Glass.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Fixes</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Fixed Codeberg support being unreliable</li>
        <li>Every Panel now Fetches its contents on open. This fixes a bug where newly added buttons could not show till you restarted the client.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Removed</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Removed our custom frame plugin now that MacOS support is built-in</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Stoat v1.4.0</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Screensharing support is now supported along with a Integrated screen picker</li>
        <li>Electron was updated to v40</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Warning ! Due to an update in the backend, you'll need to backup your settings before updating and then after doing that log back into your account and import settings.</p>

    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-audio">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
